Osgood Gunawan

New York City, NY | Rowland Heights, CA | 626-726-5957 | osgood1024@gmail.com <u>Github | Medium | personal website | LinkedIn</u>

Full-Stack Software Engineer

Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux, Adobe Xd, Figma with a background in Computer and Cognitive Science specialized in Human-Computer Interaction. As a User Experience Designer, I am deeply passionate about creating experiences that build intersections between problem-solving and design thinking. My diverse skill set in UX/UI design, team-building, communication, debugging, and pair programming combined with a STEM background has led me to love computer science and software systems.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQLite, Javascript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, MATLAB, Adobe XD, Figma, Bootstrap, Canva, Wireframing, Prototyping, Persona, User flows, Storyboarding, Interaction Design, User Experience Design, Ul & UX, User Testing

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Project Zoo - Front End | Back End | Demo

A website where you can find project ideas or share your project with the platform.

- Developed a Rails API backend with endpoints for users, comments, projects, and favorites.
- Built backend RESTful APIs service with Ruby on the Rails framework.
- Designed responsive transition animation with react spring and custom HTML/ CSS styling user interface.
- Designed the project brand logo with a graphic design platform, Canva.

Movie Review- Github

A movie review website where users can check the review before watching the shows/movies or users can leave a review after watching.

- Developed a Rails API backend with endpoints for movies, reviews, watchlists, and users.
- Showcased Ruby on Rails MVC architecture developed an entire website in 3 days with a fully functioning backend.
- Utilized movie DB API to pull and parse movies' data as well as dynamically display the most current information based on each user and destination.

Oasis - Github | Demo | Research Demo

A Web app that offers or reserves space for an event.

- Initiated the idea aspect of the project.
- Implemented the user interface and user experience with fully CSS styling.
- Investigated multiple user studies to understand user needs for reserving or offering space for an event.

EXPERIENCE

GVM Networks (PT.Global Visi Media)

Jakarta, Indonesia 07/2018 - 09/2018

UI & UX designer internship

- Revamped an old project (a mobile app) that targets the market for field owners who rent out their soccer field.
- Helped to create a gamification concept to increase user-retention and marketing strategy for user engagement in the Bolalob.com point system.
- Collaborated with mentors and UX designers from WomanTalk to remodel and develop a new concept for health wellness in women for WomanTalk.com.

Mechanical Engineering Department at California State University, Fullerton

Fullerton, CA

Human Interactive Robotics Lab Internship

05/2015 - 08/2015

- Collaborated with teammates on projects such as assembly of the robot arm-rover-system and development of a sensor-based glove for extracting human's motion.
- Presented the final project to Southern California Conferences for Undergraduate Research (SCCUR).

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Manhattan, NY

Immersive Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JS with React program

02/ 2020 - 05/2020

University California Of San Diego

La Jolla, CA

06/2019

Bachelor Science in Cognitive Science with a specialization Human-Computer Interaction

-Award: Design hackathon's (Designathon) most unique concept award rewarded \$1000 out of 28 teams.